<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide App</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_flag">City flag</string>
    <string name="city_name">Szczecinek</string>
    <string name="attractions">Attractions</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="city_image_licence">By Vercyngetorix - Own work, CC BY-SA 3.0 pl, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=35817371</string>
    <string name="about_city">is a city in Middle Pomerania, northwestern Poland with a population of more than 40,000 (2011). Formerly in the Koszalin Voivodeship (1950–1998), it has been the capital of Szczecinek County in the West Pomeranian Voivodeship since 1999. It is an important railroad junction, located along the main Poznań - Kolobrzeg line, which crosses less important lines to Chojnice, Słupsk and Runowo Pomorskie. The city boundaries were expanded in 2009 to include Świątki and Trzesieka, a total area of 48.63 square kilometres (18.78 square miles).</string>
    <string name="city_history">In 1310, the castle and town were founded under Lübeck law by Duke Wartislaw IV of Pomerania-Wolgast and modelled after Szczecin (German: Stettin) which is situated about 150 kilometres (93 miles) to the west. The initial name was Neustettin (Polish: Nowy Szczecin, German: Neustettin, Latin: Stetin Nova). It was also known as Klein Stettin (Polish: Mały Szczecin, German: Klein Stettin). In 1707 the town was known in Polish as Nowoszczecin, while the Mały Szczecin name gradually developed into the modern name Szczecinek.[1] The town was fortified to face the Brandenburgers, with a wall and palisades. In 1356 Neustettin was hit by the plague. Thankful for their survival, the Dukes Bogislaw V, Barnim IV and Wartislaw V founded the Augustine monastery Marienthron, on the Mönchsberg on the southern bank of Lake Streizigsee. Under the Duke Wartislaw VII Neustettin, from 1376 to 1395 it was the seat of his Duchy. Afterwards, it was ruled by Pomeranian Duchy: Rügenwalde (-1418), Wolgast (-1474) and Stettin (until 1618). On 15 September 1423, the great day of Neustettin, the Pomeranian dukes, the Hochmeister of the Teutonic Order and Nordic king Eric VII of Denmark met to discuss defense against the union of Brandenburg and Poland. In 1461 Neustettin was sacked, looted and burned by Polish troops and Tatars because King Casimir IV wanted to take revenge on Eric II of Pomerania-Wolgast who supported the Teutonic Knights. At the end of the Thirty Years War, Neustettin became part of Brandenburg, and in 1701 under the crown of Prussia. In 1945, the Red Army occupied the town and put it under Polish administration.</string>
    <string name="sample_long_description">This is a long description of forest path very long very, very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long. This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.This is a long description of forest path very long very very long.</string>
    <string name="image_of_place">image of place</string>
    <string-array name="places">
        <item>@string/place_1</item>
        <item>@string/place_2</item>
        <item>@string/place_3</item>
        <item>@string/place_4</item>
        <item>@string/place_5</item>
        <item>@string/place_6</item>
        <item>@string/place_7</item>
        <item>@string/place_8</item>
        <item>@string/place_9</item>
        <item>@string/place_10</item>
        <item>@string/place_11</item>
        <item>@string/place_12</item>
        <item>@string/place_holder</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="place_holder">category;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_1">history;tower;tower of the church of St. Nicholas; the tower is a remnant of the church of St. St. Nicholas, which was the oldest religious building in the city. Most probably it comes from the mid-sixteenth century. It is basically the oldest preserved monument in Szczecinek. Built in the Gothic style of material obtained after the demolition of the monastery located on the hill Marientron. From the second half of the 16th century, the church of St. Nicholas was a Lutheran temple. The earliest image of the temple is among the views of the West Pomeranian cities on the map of Lubinus and comes from 1612.;tower</string>
    <string name="place_2">history;castle;Pomeranian Duke\'s Castle;As early as at the end of XIII century, there was a Slavic settlement on the island nearby the place from which the Nizica River flows. The border nature of the settlement and its excellent defensive qualities contributed to the decision made around the year 1310 by Duke Warcislaw IV to build there a castle. This way the castle of Szczecinek became the seat of Starostes who in the name of the duke held the power here. First of them was Otto von Wedel. At the same time, the settlement on the mainland was awarded town privileges.;castle</string>
    <string name="place_3">history;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_4">history;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_5">nature;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_6">nature;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_7">nature;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_8">nature;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_9">activity;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_10">activity;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_11">activity;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <string name="place_12">activity;name;description;long description;forest_path</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_place">PlaceActivity</string>
    <string name="nature">Nature</string>
    <string name="recreation">Recreation</string>
    <string name="food">Food</string>
</resources>
