<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide App</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_flag">City flag</string>
    <string name="city_name">Szczecinek</string>
    <string name="attractions">Attractions</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="city_image_licence">By Vercyngetorix - Own work, CC BY-SA 3.0 pl, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=35817371</string>
    <string name="about_city">is a town in Middle Pomerania, northwestern Poland with a population of more than 40,000 (2011). Formerly in the Koszalin Voivodeship (1950–1998), it has been the capital of Szczecinek County in the West Pomeranian Voivodeship since 1999. It is an important railroad junction, located along the main Poznań - Kolobrzeg line, which crosses less important lines to Chojnice, Słupsk and Runowo Pomorskie. The city boundaries were expanded in 2009 to include Świątki and Trzesieka, a total area of 48.63 square kilometres (18.78 square miles).</string>
    <string name="city_history">In 1310, the castle and town were founded under Lübeck law by Duke Wartislaw IV of Pomerania-Wolgast and modelled after Szczecin (German: Stettin) which is situated about 150 kilometres (93 miles) to the west. The initial name was Neustettin (Polish: Nowy Szczecin, German: Neustettin, Latin: Stetin Nova). It was also known as Klein Stettin (Polish: Mały Szczecin, German: Klein Stettin). In 1707 the town was known in Polish as Nowoszczecin, while the Mały Szczecin name gradually developed into the modern name Szczecinek.[1] The town was fortified to face the Brandenburgers, with a wall and palisades. In 1356 Neustettin was hit by the plague. Thankful for their survival, the Dukes Bogislaw V, Barnim IV and Wartislaw V founded the Augustine monastery Marienthron, on the Mönchsberg on the southern bank of Lake Streizigsee. Under the Duke Wartislaw VII Neustettin, from 1376 to 1395 it was the seat of his Duchy. Afterwards, it was ruled by Pomeranian Duchy: Rügenwalde (-1418), Wolgast (-1474) and Stettin (until 1618). On 15 September 1423, the great day of Neustettin, the Pomeranian dukes, the Hochmeister of the Teutonic Order and Nordic king Eric VII of Denmark met to discuss defense against the union of Brandenburg and Poland. In 1461 Neustettin was sacked, looted and burned by Polish troops and Tatars because King Casimir IV wanted to take revenge on Eric II of Pomerania-Wolgast who supported the Teutonic Knights. At the end of the Thirty Years War, Neustettin became part of Brandenburg, and in 1701 under the crown of Prussia. In 1945, the Red Army occupied the town and put it under Polish administration.</string>
    <string name="image_of_place">image of place</string>
    <string name="place_1">history;Tower;Tower of the church of St. Nicholas; the tower is a remnant of the church of St. St. Nicholas, which was the oldest religious building in the city. Most probably it comes from the mid-sixteenth century. It is basically the oldest preserved monument in Szczecinek. Built in the Gothic style of material obtained after the demolition of the monastery located on the hill Marientron. From the second half of the 16th century, the church of St. Nicholas was a Lutheran temple. The earliest image of the temple is among the views of the West Pomeranian cities on the map of Lubinus and comes from 1612.;tower</string>
    <string name="place_2">history;Castle;Pomeranian Duke\'s Castle;As early as at the end of XIII century, there was a Slavic settlement on the island nearby the place from which the Nizica River flows. The border nature of the settlement and its excellent defensive qualities contributed to the decision made around the year 1310 by Duke Warcislaw IV to build there a castle. This way the castle of Szczecinek became the seat of Starostes who in the name of the duke held the power here. First of them was Otto von Wedel. At the same time, the settlement on the mainland was awarded town privileges.;castle</string>
    <string name="place_3">history;Church;Church of the Nativity of the Blessed Virgin Mary;It is a neo–gothic temple built in 1905–1908 according to the design of the Berlin architect Oskar Hoßfeld, under the supervision of the construction inspector D.A. Schäfer as an evangelical church. St. Nicholas (Neue Nikolai Kirche). The church was built of brick. Its magnificent and powerful church shape is characterized by lightness, achieved by the use of soaring windows and the ogival ornaments of the transept tops. The body of the temple, fastened outside with high buttresses, closes the hexagonal presbytery on the east side, enclosed on the sides with low annexes, and from the west a slender church tower high at 78 m. The main altar of the temple has a cupboard construction. The church organs on the choir are equipped with 1670 pipes.;church</string>
    <string name="place_4">history;Town hall;Town Hall in Szczecinek;the town hall is located at Plac Wolności. It is an eclectic building with a predominance of neo-Romanesque elements. It was built in 1852 on a rectangular plan. It is a red brick one-story building. It has large characteristic windows. The roof of the town hall is hipped and made of red roof tiles. Currently, it is the seat of municipal authorities. At the main facade there is a projection going into an octagonal tower. There is a four-sided tower on it with the date of the town hall construction. The top walls of the building and tower have a blanked attic hanging over the arcade ledge. In the corners of the town hall are placed polygonal turrets with lanterns.;town_hall</string>
    <string name="place_5">nature;Kusowo bog;Kusowo bog nature path;The "Bagno Kusowo" nature reserve was created in 2005. It protects the vegetation of the raised bog. It is one of the largest (300 ha), best-educated and preserved Baltic bogs in Poland overgrown with sphagnum peat bogs and marshy forest. A perfectly preserved northern fragment of the bog, with a non-forest central part, covered with bogs with turf wool and dwarf pine. In places shallow, peat ponds form, which is unique in Polish peat bogs. In 2004, the object was reported to the Natura 2000 network, and in 2005 a nature reserve was created here. In order to preserve the bog in good condition, active protection measures are designed and implemented - primarily, dams are built on artificial ditches draining water from the slopes of the dome. A natural path has been functioning here since 2006, allowing everyone to see the Bagno Kusowo. The observation platform is a great attraction of the nature trail on the section between the parking lot and the shore of Lake Wielatowo. The path is equipped with educational boards.;kusowo</string>
    <string name="place_6">nature;Wilczkowskie oaks;Dęby Wilczkowskie Nature Reserve;The purpose of protection is to preserve old oak trees with acidic low beechwood (Luzulo pilosae-Fagetum) and subatlantic hornbeam (Stellario holostae-Carpinetum betuli) with valuable sites of protected and endangered plants, primarily with gilt-billed gold (Gagea spathacea) and small gold (Gagea minima ), spring snow (Leucojum vernum), sweet hive (Galium odoratum), pink husk (Lathraea squamaria).;wilczkowskie</string>
    <string name="place_7">nature;Ciemino bog;Nature Reserve Bagno Ciemino;a reserve with an area of 400.30 ha, created on July 25, 1997 in order to preserve, for scientific and didactic reasons, valuable forest and peat ecosystems characteristic of the Drawskie Lakeland. It is located in the West Pomeranian Voivodeship, in the Szczecinek poviat, in the eastern part of the Borne Sulinowo commune, 1 km northeast of Łączna and 3.5 km west of Jelenino.;ciemino</string>
    <string name="place_8">nature;Diabelskie Pustacie;Nature Reserve Diabelskie Pustacie;The purpose of nature conservation in the reserve is to preserve the biocenotic systems and landscape of the two sandrier routes - the younger sandrier trail and the T plateow trail as well as the melting cuts and hills of the erosion type.The reserve is located on the site of the former "Borne Sulinowo" training ground, including the largest area heaths preserved in Western Pomerania.;pustacie</string>
    <string name="place_9">activity;Museum;Regional Museum in Szczecinek;The Regional Museum in Szczecinek is one of the oldest in the whole of Western Pomerania. It was established in 1914 and only some of the Pomeranian museums can boast of an older birth certificate. However, museum traditions should be postponed until 1866, when the retired Prussian major, F. W. Kasiski, organized a huge - as for those times - archaeological exhibition in the Szczecin armory.;muzeum</string>
    <string name="place_10">activity;Tennis Center;Regional Tennis Center;The Regional Tennis Center in Szczecinek is one of the largest facilities of this type in northern Poland, guaranteeing the highest level of training for professional athletes and great fun for novice athletes. The entire facility is adapted to the needs of disabled people.;tennis</string>
    <string name="place_11">activity;swimming pool;Town swimming pool;For 15 years, the Szczecin swimming pool guarantees the highest standard of services - both recreational and sporting. Professional swimming instructors as well as well-prepared and experienced rescuers are a professional help. Almost every day of the year is a training place for hundreds of children and young people who implement their training program - both school and club, m or individual. After training, you will successfully find a place and idea for regeneration of a tired body.;pool</string>
    <string name="place_12">activity;Island ;Mouse Island ;Mouse Island is one of the most picturesque and charming places Szczecinek. Connected to the mainland by a dike, even before the Second World War, was a favourite place of rest and entertainment of the residents of our city. Its existence and later period of greatest prosperity Mouse Island certainly owed to Hugo Schumacher. Mr Schumacher, not without some difficulties from the municipal authorities, decided to build at this location restaurant, which over the years has grown into the landscape of Szczecinek, becoming a permanent part of the cultural landscape.;island</string>
    <string name="place_13">food;Due Gusti;Trattoria Due Gusti;Trattoria Due Gusti is an enlarged version of the previous small Italian store, which was located at ul. Wyszynski under the same name, which gives all guests a guarantee of excellent quality dishes and excellent taste. Because the menu is just like the Italian cuisine, it is light, full of pasta, beautiful-looking and tasty salads, meat dishes and thin-crust pizza.;duegusti</string>
    <string name="place_14">food;Piano Bar;Piano Bar in the castle;With the opening of the ZAMEK Conference Center, the next Piano Bar appeared on the map of Szczecinek attractions. Fact, some say that this is just another place where you can drink a beer, but … Behind the iron doors, in the atmospheric castle cellars resonate with jazz rhythms played live by various artists, the sung poetry introduces a wistful mood and the well-being improves Mug of fine beer or an elegant glass of wine. Together with our guests, we want to create a unique meeting place.;piano</string>
    <string name="place_15">food;Sint Ji;Lounge Bar Sint Ji;Cocktail bar with a wide range of drinks, wines and champagnes, terrace, jaccuzi on the terrace (unguarded);sintji</string>
    <string name="place_16">food;Oregano;Oregano Burgers and steaks;just burgers and steaks;oregano</string>
    <string name="title_activity_place">Place description</string>
    <string name="nature">Nature</string>
    <string name="recreation">Recreation</string>
    <string name="food">food</string>
    <string name="about_app" >The application uses information from wikipedia, from city websites and state forests</string>
    <string-array name="places">
        <item>@string/place_1</item>
        <item>@string/place_2</item>
        <item>@string/place_3</item>
        <item>@string/place_4</item>
        <item>@string/place_5</item>
        <item>@string/place_6</item>
        <item>@string/place_7</item>
        <item>@string/place_8</item>
        <item>@string/place_9</item>
        <item>@string/place_10</item>
        <item>@string/place_11</item>
        <item>@string/place_12</item>
        <item>@string/place_13</item>
        <item>@string/place_14</item>
        <item>@string/place_15</item>
        <item>@string/place_16</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
